<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://lsst-sal.tuc.noao.edu/schema/SALCommandSet.xsl"?>
<SALCommandSet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://lsst-sal.tuc.noao.edu/schema/SALCommandSet.xsd">
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_resetCorrection</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Reset the current wavefront error correction. The aggregated degree of freedom in optical feedback control will be reset to the initial state.</Description>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_issueCorrection</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Issue the wavefront correction to subsystems based on the most recent OFC outputs.</Description>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_rejectCorrection</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Reject the most recent wavefront correction.</Description>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_selectSources</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Run source selection algorithm for a specific field and visit configuration.</Description>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>ra</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Right Ascension of the field in ICRS coordinates.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>float</IDL_Type>
      <Units>hourangle</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>decl</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Declination of the field in ICRS coordinates.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>float</IDL_Type>
      <Units>degree</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>pa</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Sky position angle of the observation. As defined by the IAU, this the angle measured relative to the north celestial pole (NCP), turning positive into the direction of the right ascension.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>float</IDL_Type>
      <Units>degree</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>filter</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Enumeration with the filter used in the observation.</Description>
      <!-- Enumeration: FilterType -->
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>mode</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Enumeration specifying the wfs mode.</Description>
      <!-- Enumeration: Mode -->
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_preProcess</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Pre-process image for WEP. The outputs of this command are donut images that are ready for curvature wavefront sensing.</Description>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>visitId</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Image visit id number. This is a unique identifier for each image and consists of the date of the observation plus an integer iterator, e.g. 2020103000040 for the 40th image taken in October, 30, 2020.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>useOCPS</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Use the OCS-Controlled Pipeline System (OCPS) to process data remotely?</Description>
      <IDL_Type>boolean</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>config</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Yaml configuration string with additional parameters to be passed to ISR and other pre-process tasks. If options are invalid command will be rejected. If not given, use the standard configuration.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>string</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_runWEP</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Process wavefront data, either full focal plane mode (Comcam and LSSTCam) or wavefront sensors. If only visitId is provided it assumes wavefront sensor mode. If visitId and extraId is provided it assumes full focal plane mode. MTAOS will determine if it is ComCam or LSSTCam based on the input images. If useOCPS=True, processing is done remotely using the OCPS CSC. For LSSTCam full array mode only OCPS processing is supported. Before running this command it is advisable to run selectSources and preProcess commands on the input image(s), otherwise MTAOS will have to run those processes before running wep.</Description>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>visitId</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Image visit id number. This is a unique identifier for each image and consists of the date of the observation plus an integer iterator, e.g. 2020103000040 for the 40th image taken in October, 30, 2020.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>extraId</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Extra focal image visit id number (optional). Same as visitId, if different than zero, the command assumes this is an Intra/Focal sequence, otherwise it assumes Corner Wavefront Sensor.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>useOCPS</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Use OCS-Controlled Pipeline System (OCPS) to process data remotely? Ideally this should match the value of a previous preProcess command. If runWEP and preProcess run with different useOCPS setups, runWEP will run normally but will take longer as it will have to repeat the steps of preProcess. A warning message will inform the users of these conditions.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>boolean</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>config</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Yaml configuration string with additional parameters to be passed to WEP process. If options are invalid command will be rejected. If not given, use the standard configuration.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>string</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_runOFC</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Run OFC on the latest wavefront errors data. Before running this command, you must have ran runWEP at least once. This command will run ofc to compute correction but won't apply them. Use issueCorrection to apply the corrections. This allow users to evaluate whether the corrections are sensible before applying them.</Description>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>userGain</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Gain value between 0 and 1. Set to -1 to ignore user gain.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>float</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>config</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Yaml configuration string with additional parameters to be passed to OFC. If options are invalid command will be rejected. If not given, use the standard configuration.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>string</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
  </SALCommand>
  <SALCommand>
    <Subsystem>MTAOS</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>MTAOS_command_addAberration</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Utility command to add aberration to the system based on user provided wavefront errors. The command assume uniform aberration on all sensors.</Description>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>wf</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Array with z4-z22 terms of wavefront errors. Indexes are considered to be ANSI (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zernike_polynomials#OSA/ANSI_standard_indices).</Description>
      <IDL_Type>double</IDL_Type>
      <Units>micron</Units>
      <Count>19</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>config</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Yaml configuration string with additional parameters to be passed to OFC. If options are invalid command will be rejected. If not given, use the standard configuration.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>string</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
  </SALCommand>
</SALCommandSet>
