<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://lsst-sal.tuc.noao.edu/schema/SALEventSet.xsl"?>
<SALEventSet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://lsst-sal.tuc.noao.edu/schema/SALEventSet.xsd">
  <Enumeration>GuiderStatus_Stopped,GuiderStatus_Starting,GuiderStatus_Guiding,GuiderStatus_Error</Enumeration>
  <SALEvent>
    <Subsystem>Guider</Subsystem>
    <EFDB_Topic>Guider_logevent_guidingStatus</EFDB_Topic>
    <Description>Event published when a guiding operatation starts, stops or resumes. It contains the parameters used to configure the guider (see startGuiding command) and the current status.</Description>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>roiXLeft</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Vector with 8 elements specifying the origin of the guider ROI window in the x-axis for each guider sensor.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>pixel</Units>
      <Count>8</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>roiXRight</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Vector with 8 elements specifying the end of the guider ROI window in the x-axis for each guider sensor. If roiXLeft=roiXRight=0, for a particular element of both arrays, it assumes no guider region for the equivalent guider sensor. For each valid entry in roiXRight/roiXLeft the width must respect the ROI constrains (see requirement CA-TS-GDR-ICD-0006 in LSE-66).</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>pixel</Units>
      <Count>8</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>roiYBottom</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Vector with 8 elements specifying the origin of the guider ROI window in the y-axis for each guider sensor.</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>pixel</Units>
      <Count>8</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>roiYTop</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Vector with 8 elements specifying the end of the guider ROI window in the y-axis for each guider sensor. If roiXBottom=roiXTop=0, for a particular element of both arrays, it assumes no guider region for the equivalent guider sensor. For each valid entry in roiXBottom/roiXTop the width must respect the ROI constrains (see requirement CA-TS-GDR-ICD-0006 in LSE-66).</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>pixel</Units>
      <Count>8</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>expTime</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Exposure time in milliseconds. All guider sensors will use the same exposure time (CA-TS-GDR-ICD-0034 LSE-66). Limits must respect detector integration time constrains (see requirement CA-TS-GDR-ICD-0034 in LSE-66).</Description>
      <IDL_Type>float</IDL_Type>
      <Units>ms</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>binning</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Binnig factor. All guider sensors will use the same binning factor. Limits must respect detector bining constrains (see requirement CA-TS-GDR-ICD-0042 in LSE-66).</Description>
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>pixel</Units>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </item>
    <item>
      <EFDB_Name>status</EFDB_Name>
      <Description>Enumeration with the current guiding status. When guider is not running status will be GuiderStatus_Stopped, this could either be when the guider is first enabled or after a stopGuiding command. When guider is initializing a guider sequence but has not achieved stable guiding operation status will be GuiderStatus_Starting. When stable guiding operation is stabilished, status will be GuiderStatus_Guiding. If an error occurred, and the guider is going to FAULT state, status is GuiderStatus_Error. Information about errors will be available in errorCode topic.</Description>
      <!-- Enumeration: GuiderStatus -->
      <IDL_Type>long</IDL_Type>
      <Units>unitless</Units>
      <Count>8</Count>
    </item>
  </SALEvent>
</SALEventSet>
